<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michal Smielak</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michal Smielak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Michał Śmielak. I&amp;rsquo;m an wildlife biologist, working in the field handling animals and in the office wrangling data. Originally from Poland, over the years I have been involved in projects in Europe, Australia and Africa.
I am interested in various aspects of animal ecology, including (but not limited to) behavioural ecology of mammals, reptiles and amphibians, conservation, ecosystem management and human-wildlife conflicts.
I write code (mostly in R) to transform raw data collected in the field into results and conservation outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>/photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/photo/</guid>
      <description>I take photos, mostly of nature and landscapes. Some of my photos won awards in competitions.
I am always happy to give permission for my photos to be used for a good cause. If you are a non-profit and would like to use one of my photos to promote your work, an educational or conservation project, please get in touch with me.
If you want to buy one of my photos - either as a print or for digital use, send me a message and we can work out details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproductible code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>Below you will find various examples of reproductible code that I came up with over the years - mostly functions and packages developped in R to help with ecological data analysis. Hopefully, this will be updated over time.
 moonlit package 
moonlit - R package I&amp;rsquo;ve been deveoping since 2018. It is a model to predict moonlight intensity on the ground for any given place and time, based on the position of the moon and a number of correction factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing projects 2014-
The community ecology of threatened, critical-weightrange, terrestrial mammals in response to wild canid and feral cat control.
PhD project, part of the Predator-Prey-Plan-People project, Invasive Animals Cooperative Research Centre.
Trapping and handling animals, using GPS and VHF telemetry to measure spatio-temporal patterns of activity; extensive remote camera monitoring; experiments measuring non-direct effects of predation; using drones to collect hi-resolution habitat data; data analysis and modelling using R and QGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/technology/</guid>
      <description>Various electronic bibs and bobs, mostly for use in wildlife research.
 wilduino 
wilduino is a project of an animal-borne logger. In its concept, it is a modular, open-source device consisting of a microcontroller board and a range of &amp;ldquo;shields&amp;rdquo;, similar to Arduino desing, but much smaller and optimised for low power consumption. First prototypes include GPS, 9 DOF IMU and altimeter to track 3D movements of animals. Baseboard (Arduino-based) also has LoRa communication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
